A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, 55th Street, Series 16 FA362
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files of Kathy Huldrum and Nancy Towell, 1970-1974; 5
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Staats, Elmer B., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 408)
    Comptroller General of the United States.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Baker, Howard H., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 409)
    United States Senator.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Bentsen, Lloyd M., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 410)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Blatnik, John A., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 411)
    United States Representative.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Buckley, James A., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 412)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Clarke, General Frederick J., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 413)
    Executive Director.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Gee, Edwin A., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 414)
    Public Member and a Senior Vice President at the DuPont Corporation.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Gianelli, William R., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 415)
    Public Member and Director of The Resources Company, Department of Water Resources, California.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Grover, James R., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 416)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Harsha, William H., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 417)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Jones, Robert E., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 418)
    United States Representative and Vice-Chairman.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Kudukis, Raymond, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 419)
    Public Member and Director of Cleveland Department of Public Works.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Muskie, Edmund S., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 420)
    United States Senator and Vice Chairman.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Randolph, Jennings, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 421)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Wright, Carl E., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 422)
    Public Member and Chairman of the Arkansas Department of Pollution Control and Ecology.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Commission Members - Wright, James C., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 423)
    Untied States Representative.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Draft Letter, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 424)
    On the Chairmanship of the National Study Commission, the precursor to the NCWQ.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Environmental Protection Agency, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 425)
    EPA Publication "A Citizen's Guide to Clean Water," January 1974.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Environmental Protection Agency, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 426)
    Report on Water Quality issued by the EPA, November 1973.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - "Federalism and Clean Water", 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 427)
    By Dr. Harvey Lieber, Harvard University.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - "Federalism and Clean Water", 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 428)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - "Federalism and Clean Water", 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 429)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Governor's Suggestions, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 430)
    For committee liaisons.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - June 6, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 431)
    Agenda for the Second Meeting of the NCWQ.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - July 12, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 432)
    Agenda and materials from the Executive Committee Meeting.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - July 31, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 433)
    Agenda and materials for the NCWQ meeting.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - September 26, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 434)
    Meeting Book for the NCWQ meeting.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - October 4, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 435)
    Minutes of previous meetings (July 12, 31) to be approved at October 4 meeting.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - October 4, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 436)
    Meeting book for the NCWQ meeting.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - December 6, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 437)
    Meeting books for the NCWQ meeting.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - December 6, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 438)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - December 6, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 439)
    Minutes of the December 6 meeting.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - February 26, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 440)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - March 7, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 441)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - April 9, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 442)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - April 24, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 443)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - June 6, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 444)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - June 6, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 445)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - July 18, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 446)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - July 25, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 447)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Meetings - July 25, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 448)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Memoranda (Box 27, Folder 449)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Memoranda - Clark, General P.J., January 1974-March 1974 (Box 27, Folder 450)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Memoranda - Clark, General P.J., April 1974-September 1974 (Box 27, Folder 451)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Memoranda - Diamond, Henry L. (Box 27, Folder 452)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Memoranda - Mitchell, Donna, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 453)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Memoranda - Mitchell, Donna, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 454)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - National Research Council (Box 27, Folder 455)
    Correspondence and reports from the NRC on issues relating to Water Quality.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - National Study Commission (Box 27, Folder 456)
    May 1973 organization that was the genus for the National Commission on Water Quality.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - National Water Commission, 1968-1973 (Box 27, Folder 457)
    Report that resulted in the founding of the Commission.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Study Plan, October 1973 (Box 28, Folder 458)
    Draft for the Commission's goals.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Study Plan, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 459)
    Designs for the Water Quality Commission.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Statement by NAR, April 5, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 460)
    On the Water Commission.
  - Pending Files - "Appointments" (Box 28, Folder 461)
    These are office files that accumulated information that were never filed into more precise files. The information ranges from requests for appointments with NAR, invitations to NAR to speak, and internal memoranda regarding future events. There are also a series of dated folders for late 1973 and early 1974 that concerned appointments for those months. The original file names have been retained to give some understanding as to the rationale behind the folder contents.
  - Pending Files - "Hold Files - Miscellaneous Regrets" (Box 28, Folder 462)
  - Pending Files - "Miscellaneous" (Box 28, Folder 463)
  - Pending Files - "Miscellaneous" (Box 28, Folder 464)
  - Pending Files - "Miscellaneous Holds - Futures" (Box 29, Folder 465)
  - Pending Files - "Nancy Towell - Miscellaneous" (Box 29, Folder 466)
  - Pending Files - "To Do File - Nancy Towell" (Box 29, Folder 467)
  - Pending Files - "November 1973" (Box 29, Folder 468)
  - Pending Files - "December 1973" (Box 29, Folder 469)
  - Pending Files - "February 1974" (Box 29, Folder 470)
  - Pending Files - "March 1974" (Box 29, Folder 471)
  - Pending Files - "April 1974" (Box 29, Folder 472)
  - Pending Files - "May 1974" (Box 29, Folder 473)
  - Pending Files - "June 1974" (Box 29, Folder 474)
  - President's Foreign Intelligence Advisory Board, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 475)
    White House Memoranda for the government board that NAR was a member of in 1974.
  - Press Conferences - February 11, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 476)
  - Press Conferences - March 4, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 477)
  - Press Conferences - May 6, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 478)
  - Press Conferences - May 31, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 479)
  - Press Conferences - June 5, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 480)
  - Press Conferences - June 11, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 481)
  - Press Conferences - August 21, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 482)
  - Press Conferences - August 31, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 483)
  - Press Conferences - September 3, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 484)
  - Prisoner of War Luncheon, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 485)
    Luncheon sponsored by NAR to celebrate the freeing of several POW's held in Southeast Asia.
  - Receipts (Box 30, Folder 486)
    Petty cash receipts of various staff members to cover miscellaneous expenses.
  - Reid, Ogden (Box 30, Folder 487)
    Transcript of telephone conversation with the congressman.
  - Reports - The Admiral Gorshkow Series, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 488)
  - Reports - "An Agenda for the United States Third Century", October 1973 (Box 30, Folder 489)
    By Russell W. Peterson.
  - Reports - "Detente: An Evaluation", August 1974 (Box 30, Folder 490)
    From the Senate Armed Services Committee, subcommittee on Arms Control.
  - Reports - "The 'Dismal Science' Comes of Age: Economics in America's Third Century", March 1974 (Box 30, Folder 491)
    By Marina V. N. Whitman.
  - Reports - "The Ends of Federalism", November 1974 (Box 30, Folder 492)
    By Martin Diamond, summarized by Peter J. Wallison.
  - Reports - "The Ethos of the American Legal Process", June 1974 (Box 30, Folder 493)
    By Philip Selznick.
  - Reports - "The Impact of Exploding Oil Costs on the World Financial and Economic System", September 1974 (Box 30, Folder 494)
    By Walter J. Levy.
  - Reports - "Implications of Exploding World Oil Costs", January 1974 (Box 30, Folder 495)
  - Reports - "International Cooperation in Energy", June 1974 (Box 30, Folder 496)
    By G. A. Wagner.
  - Reports - "International Trade and Monetary Systems, Inflation and the Relationships Among Differing Economic Systems", August 1974 (Box 30, Folder 497)
  - Reports - "New York Utilities in the Early Seventies" (Box 31, Folder 498)
    By William K. Jones.
  - Reports - "New York Utilities in the Early Seventies" (Box 31, Folder 499)
  - Reports - "Prospects for the Atlantic World", April 1974 (Box 31, Folder 500)
    From the Bilderberg Meetings of the Megeve Conference.
  - Reports - "A Republican Approach to the Great Issues", July 1960 (Box 31, Folder 501)
    By Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Reports - "Research on Growth: An Inventory of Efforts in the United States and Elsewhere", March 1974 (Box 31, Folder 502)
    Published by the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars.
  - Reports - "Wage-Price Policy and the Eisenhower Administration", May 1974 (Box 31, Folder 503)
    By Scott Gordon.
  - Reports - "Wage-Price Policy and the Johnson Administration", Summer 1974 (Box 31, Folder 504)
    By James L. Cochrane.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Assistants, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 505)
    Letters to governors introducing individuals to assist them during the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Celebrity Night, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 506)
    May 10 dinner held at the Rainbow Room.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Celebrity Night - Invitation Lists, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 507)
  - Republican Governors Conference - Celebrity Night - Seating Plans and Table Assignments, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 508)
  - Republican Governors Conference - Contributions, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 509)
    Letters to individuals soliciting funds to help defray the costs of the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Invitation Letter, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 510)
    Letter from NAR inviting the Republican governors to attend the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Gifts for Governors, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 511)
    Letters to retailers and other individuals asking for gift suggestions for the governors and their wives.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Ladies Luncheon, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 512)
    May 10, 1973 luncheon at the 21 Club for the wives of the governors.
  - Republican Governors Conference - May 9 Dinner, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 513)
    Reception and dinner for the governors and their wives at 812 Fifth Avenue, hosted by Governor and Mrs. NAR.
  - Republican Governors Conference - May 12 Luncheon, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 514)
    Reception and luncheon held at Pocantico for selected governors and their wives.
  - Republican Governors Conference - McHugh, Dorothy, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 515)
    Letters of thanks from governors' wives to McHugh who assisted with the planning of the women's events.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Menus, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 516)
    Suggestions and menus for parties during the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 517)
    Working file of documents related to the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Photos, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 518)
    Letter to governors enclosing photos of the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Planning File, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 519)
    Documents regarding the planning of the conference and different parts of it.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Schedules, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 520)
    Copies of schedules of events for the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Shopping, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 521)
    Listing of stores offering their services to the governors and their wives attending the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - State Dinner - Invitation Lists, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 522)
    Invitation lists for the official state dinner held on May 11.
  - Republican Governors Conference - State Dinner - Seating Charts and Program, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 523)
    The official program and seating charts for the State Dinner held on May 11.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Thank You Letters - Letters and Bills, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 524)
    Letters to individuals who were helpful during the Republican Governors' Conference. Bills for parties and receptions.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Thank You Letters - Letters, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 525)
    Letters of thanks to individuals who assisted with the planning, running, and operation of the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Thank You Letters - Lists, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 526)
    Index cards and lists of those individuals scheduled to receive a thank you letter.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Theatre Tickets, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 527)
    Background material and orders for tickets to Broadway shows arranged for the governors and their wives.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Things To Do, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 528)
    Listings copied from various tourist books on things to do in New York during the conference.
  - Republican Governors Conference - Women's Program, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 529)
    Letter from Nancy Towell to wives of governors explaining the plans for the governors' wives at the conference.
  - "The Rockefeller Record", 1973 (Box 33, Folder 530)
    Press release listing NAR's accomplishments as Governor of New York, 1959-1973, issued upon the announcement of his intention to resign as Governor, December 11, 1973.
  - Rosenberg, Judge Gustave G. (Box 33, Folder 531)
    Judge appointed by NAR, Rosenberg received an award where NAR was asked to provide information on the selection of Judge Rosenberg.
  - Speeches - Colorado, January 31, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 532)
  - Speeches - New York City, February 11, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 533)
  - Speeches - New York City, March 14, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 534)
  - Speeches - New York City, April 16, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 535)
  - Speeches - New York City, April 23, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 536)
  - Speeches - Edison, New Jersey, June 5, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 537)
  - Speeches - Uniondale, New York, June 12, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 538)
  - Speeches - New York City, June 13, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 539)
  - Speeches - Toronto, Canada, July 26, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 540)
  - Speeches - The White House, August 20, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 541)
  - State Study Commission for New York City, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 542)
    Miscellaneous reports, correspondence, and memoranda from the 1971 commission established by Governor Rockefeller.
  - TV Show - "Eternal Light", May 26, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 543)
  - Transportation Bond Issue, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 544)
  - Transportation Bond Issue, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 545)
  - Trips - Family Trip to California and Disneyland, Summer 1971 (Box 33, Folder 546)
  - Trips - Western Trip, Summer 1972 (Box 33, Folder 547)
  - UN Ambassadors Dinner, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 548)
  - United Nations 25th Anniversary Committee, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 549)
  - Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings - Background, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 550)
  - Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings - Issues, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 551)
  - Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings - Memoranda - John E. Lockwood, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 552)
  - Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings - NAR Notes, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 553)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See box 40, oversized material
  - Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings - Sample Questions, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 554)
  - Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings - Testimony (Draft with corrections), 1974 (Box 33, Folder 555)
  - Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings - Testimony (Draft), 1974 (Box 33, Folder 556)
  - Westchester Political Report, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 557)
  - Wholesale Tobacco Distributors of New York (Box 33, Folder 558)
  - Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings - NAR Notes, [1974]; 18" x 25" (Box 40, Folder 604)
    NAR's handwritten outlines for his testimony at the Vice Presidential confirmation hearings in the fall of 1974. 4 pages, no date.
    Removed from Box 33, Folder 553
  - Vice Presidential Confirmation Hearings - NAR Notes, [1974]; 18" x 24" (Box 40, Folder 605)
    NAR's handwritten outline illustrating how economic and social issues are interconnected. Titled "Range of Desirable and Realistic Objectives for 1985," they were presumably made in the context of his chairmanship of the National Commission on Water Quality. 1 page, no date.
- Invitations, 1972-1974; 6
  This subseries is Nancy Towell's invitation file. It is divided into two parts: Invitations Received, which includes invitations to Rockefeller to attend various events, fund raisers, dinners, receptions, openings, etc.; and Letters Out, which consists of carbon copies of Rockefeller's letters of regret. Letters Out also contains some staff memos to Rockefeller asking him whether to accept or regret an invitation, and interoffice memoranda regarding Rockefeller's schedule.
  - Invitations Received - December 1973 (Box 34, Folder 559)
  - Invitations Received - January 1974 (Box 34, Folder 560)
  - Invitations Received - February 1974 (Box 34, Folder 561)
  - Invitations Received - March 1974 (Box 34, Folder 562)
  - Invitations Received - April 1974 (Box 34, Folder 563)
  - Invitations Received - May 1974 (Box 34, Folder 564)
  - Invitations Received - June 1974 (Box 34, Folder 565)
  - Invitations Received - July 1974 (Box 35, Folder 566)
  - Invitations Received - August 1974 (Box 35, Folder 567)
  - Invitations Received - September 1974 (Box 35, Folder 568)
  - Invitations Received - October 1974 (Box 35, Folder 569)
  - Invitations Received - November 1974 (Box 35, Folder 570)
  - Invitations Received - December 1974 (Box 36, Folder 571)
  - Invitations Received - January/February 1974 (Box 36, Folder 572)
  - Letters Out - 1972, No date given (Box 36, Folder 573)
  - Letters Out - January 1973 (Box 36, Folder 574)
  - Letters Out - January 1973 (Box 36, Folder 575)
  - Letters Out - February 1973 (Box 36, Folder 576)
  - Letters Out - February 1973 (Box 36, Folder 577)
  - Letters Out - March 1973 (Box 36, Folder 578)
  - Letters Out - March 1973 (Box 36, Folder 579)
  - Letters Out - April 1973 (Box 36, Folder 580)
  - Letters Out - April 1973 (Box 36, Folder 581)
  - Letters Out - May 1973 (Box 36, Folder 582)
  - Letters Out - May 1973 (Box 36, Folder 583)
  - Letters Out - June 1973 (Box 37, Folder 584)
  - Letters Out - June 1973 (Box 37, Folder 585)
  - Letters Out - July 1973 (Box 37, Folder 586)
  - Letters Out - July 1973 (Box 37, Folder 587)
  - Letters Out - August 1973 (Box 37, Folder 588)
  - Letters Out - August 1973 (Box 37, Folder 589)
  - Letters Out - September 1973 (Box 37, Folder 590)
  - Letters Out - September 1973 (Box 37, Folder 591)
  - Letters Out - October 1973 (Box 37, Folder 592)
  - Letters Out - October 1973 (Box 37, Folder 593)
  - Letters Out - November 1973 (Box 38, Folder 594)
  - Letters Out - November 1973 (Box 38, Folder 595)
  - Letters Out - December 1973 (Box 38, Folder 596)
  - Letters Out - December 1973 (Box 38, Folder 597)
  - Letters Out - 1973, No date given (Box 38, Folder 598)
  - Letters Out - 1974, No date given (Box 38, Folder 599)
  - Letters Out - 1974, No date given (Box 38, Folder 600)
  - Letters Out - 1974, Miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 601)
  - Letters Out - 1974, Miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 602)
  - Scheduling, January 1974 (Box 39, Folder 603)